ETHAN LAM

Project Manager, Data Scientist

Saskatoon, SK. 306-371-5783, <u>ethan.lamhai@gmail.com</u> Linkedin: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ethanlamhai/</u>

Github: https://github.com/thonglamhai/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With over 17 years of software development experience, my expertise lies in leading large-scale projects and teams, utilizing a diverse range of methodologies including Waterfall, Agile, and Hybrid approaches. Throughout my professional journey, I have successfully delivered numerous projects for clients across the globe on various domains such as Edtech, Fintech, Data, internal tools...

SKILLS

- Project management: PMP, PSM1
- Microsoft Project
- C++. .NET. API
- Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall.
- Excel. VBA
- Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn
- Python, SQL, Flask
- Jira, Azure DevOps

- Postgres, MSSQL
- VS Code, Google Collab, Anaconda
- Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Vietnamese

PROJECTS

Stock Price Forecasting

The project is to develop a forecasting system to predict the stock price as well as its support and resistance level. Tech stacks: pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, panda-tas, tensorflow, k-means clustering

Loan Prediction

The project is used to identify the probability of getting loan approval from a borrower. It is useful to understand the factors that impact to the results (approved or not).

Tech stacks: pandas, numpy, statistical modeling, Tableau

Crop Yield Analysis

Crop Yield plays an important role in the agriculture business in a province such as Saskatchewan. A reliable Crop Yield prediction system would be beneficial for insurance companies as well as farmers and investors to plan.

Tech stacks: pandas, numpy, geopandas, ARIMA, K-means

EXPERIENCE

Head of Development

January 2019 - March 2023

• Established the development processes and software quality metrics, focusing on Agile/Scrum. It is key for the company to be successfully certified by ISO 9001 and ISO 27001.

- Reviewed and approved all the project management plans, and technical solutions from project teams to ensure the project's success.
- Fostered the learning mindset of the organization, resulting in 30% of employees having a certification in Azure, AWS, PMP, or Scrum Master.
- Collaborated with other departments such as HR, Marketing, and Finance to thoroughly align recruitment, employee benefits, and revenue.
- Key Achievement: The development team size has tripled to over 200 members within 3 years, raising revenue to increase 5 times. Moreover, the company's competency has expanded to new domains such as Cloud and Data.

Senior Project Manager 2010 - 2019

- Managed project-related matters and acted as the main contact point between the project team and clients.
- Trained development team about Scrum and processes to increase the effectiveness and productivity of the team.
- Provided estimation, risk evaluation, project charter, and project management plans for approval and execution.
- Foster positive relationships with internal teams, partners, and vendors through proactive communication.
- Key Achievement: Successfully delivered multiple projects for clients, for example: a Housing management system for a UK client which is being used by 400 Social Housing Organizations and over 5 million tenants.

Senior Software Engineer

2005 - 2010

- Led a development team to take handover successfully and became the main development source for Alcatel-Lucent NodeB devices, developing call and high-speed channels.
- Migrated an application from Visual Basic to Visual C++ for a Japanese client to let them maintain it more easily.
- Implemented, tested, and fixed bugs for Nortel Multiservice Provider Edge in Ottawa.
- Key achievement: contributed to the expansion of the ODC team from 5 to 20 members after delivering projects on time and good quality.

EDUCATION

Data Science September 2023

Lighthouse Labs, Toronto, ON

Automation & Digital Agriculture Specialist

Palette Skills, Toronto, ON

August 2023

Bachelor of Computer Science University of Natural Sciences, VN

CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Professional (PMP)
Professional Scrum Master I (PSM I)
PMI-ACP (planned August 2023)

AWARDS

Second place at Cultivator 24 Hour Startup Best Project Manager of FPT Software 2018